早在光出现之前 世界是一片黑暗
Long before the birth of light, there was darkness,
那黑暗孕育了黑暗精灵
and from that darkness came the Dark Elves.
一千年前
Millennia ago
最残暴的黑暗精灵 马勒基斯
the most ruthless of their kind, Malekith,
企图将我们的宇宙
sought to transform our universe
重归于无尽黑夜
back into one of eternal night.
要实现这邪恶的计划
Such evil was possible
他必须借助以太粒子的力量
through the power of the Aether,
那是能带来无限毁灭的古老武器
an ancient force of infinite destruction.
马勒基斯
阿斯加德的军队攻来了
阿斯加德的圣军
The noble of armies of Asgard,
在我父亲包尔王的率领下
led by my father, King Bor,
对这些邪恶的生灵发起了伟大的战争
waged a mighty war against these creatures.
派出诅咒战士
九大王国的汇聚渐渐形成
As the nine worlds converged above him
马勒基斯终于可以释放以太粒子
Malekith could at last unleash the Aether.
但阿斯加德从他手上夺走了那武器
But Asgard ripped the weapon from his grasp.
没了武器 黑暗精灵就此战败
Without it, the Dark Elves fell.
尽管大势已去
With the battle all but lost
马勒基斯仍不惜牺牲他的部下
Malekith sacrificed his own people
妄图与阿斯加德军队同归于尽
in a desperate attempt to lay waste to Asgard's army.
消灭他们 我们才能生存
这场战争还远没有结束
马勒基斯被击败 以太粒子也被摧毁
Malekith was vanquished, and the Aether was no more.
至少我们以为是这样
Or so we were led to believe...
陛下 是否要摧毁以太粒子
Sire, the Aether, shall we destroy it?
只可惜它的力量太过强大 我们无法摧毁
If only we could, but its power is too great.
将它深埋
Bury it deep.
藏在没人能找到的地方
Somewhere no one will ever find it.
雷神 黑暗世界
洛基
Loki.
你好 母亲
Hello, mother.
你为我骄傲吗
Have I made you proud.
求求你 别让事情变得更糟
Please, don't make this worse.
怎样才算更糟
Define "worse".
够了
Enough!
我要单独跟犯人谈谈
I will speak to the prisoner alone.
有何必要如此大惊小怪
I really don't see what all the fuss is about.
你还没认识到你罪行的严重性吗
Do you not truly feel the gravity of your crimes?
你所到之处 必是战争 毁灭与死亡
Wherever you go there is war, ruin and death.
我是作为仁慈的神去米德加德
I went down to Midgard to rule the people of Earth
统治地球人民
as a benevolent god,
就像你一样
just like you.
我们不是神
We are not gods.
我们跟人类一样 出生 生活然后死去
We are born, we live, we die, just as humans do.
但是我们能活五千年
Give or take five thousand years.
这一切都是因为你想要王位
All this because Loki desires a throne.
这是我与生俱来的权利
It's my birthright!
你与生俱来的权利
Your birthright
是一出生
was to die...
就死去
as a child!
你本被丢弃在冰冷的岩石上
Cast out onto a frozen rock.
如果不是我当时收留了你
If I had not taken you in
此刻你就不会站在这里憎恨我
you would not be here now to hate me.
如果我该被处死 那发发慈悲
If I am for the axe, then for mercy's sake,
赶紧动手吧
just swing it.
我并非不喜欢和你谈话
It's not that I don't love our little talks,
只是…
it's just...
我的确不喜欢
I don't love them.
你还活着 完全是因为弗丽嘉不忍杀你
Frigga is the only reason you are still alive
你以后休想再见她了
and you will never see her again.
你会在地牢里度过余生
You will spend the rest of your days in the dungeons.
那托尔呢
And what of Thor?
我在牢里关到死 你却要封那个蠢货为王吗
You'll make that witless oaf king while I rot in chains?
托尔必须尽力弥补你造成的损害
Thor must strive to undo the damage you have done,
他将恢复九大王国的秩序 之后
he will bring order to the nine Realms and then,
是的 他会成为王
yes, he will be king.
华纳海姆
局面完全在我掌控之中
I've got this completely under control!
难怪四处火光连天
Is that why everything's on fire!
不用谢
You're welcome.
交给你了
All yours.
你好
Hello.
我接受你的投降
I accept your surrender.
还有谁
Anyone else?
也许下次我们该直接拿块头大的下手
Perhaps next time we should start with the big one.
接下来去哪
Where do we go next?
霍根 九大王国都已基本恢复安宁
Hogun, the peace is nearly won across the Nine Realms.
你该留下
You should stay here
与你的人民在一起 这也是你心之所向
be with your people where your heart is,
迟点回阿斯加德也无妨
Asgard can wait.
多谢你了
You have my thanks.
我也该谢你
As you have mine.
海姆达尔 可以走了
Heimdall, when you're ready.
阿斯加德
华纳海姆安定了吗
Is Vanaheim secure?
是的 诺恩海姆和里亚也是
As are Nornheim and Ria.
但如果您率军亲征 战事必能更早结束
Though our work would have gone more quickly with you at the fore.
你一定把我当成一块面包了
You must think I'm a piece of bread
需要时常涂上甜言蜜语
that needs to be buttered so heavily.
我不是这个意思
That was not my intent.
彩虹桥被毁之后 这是九大王国
For the first time since Bifrost was destroyed,
第一次重归安宁
the Nine Realms are at peace.
他们会因此铭记我们的强大
They're well reminded of our strength
而你也赢得了他们的敬意和我的谢意
and you have earned their respect and my gratitude.
谢谢您
Thank you.
一切都安定了 除了你茫然若失的心
Nothing out of order except your confused and distracted heart.
这与简·福斯特无关 父王
This isn't about Jane Foster, father.
人类的生命转瞬即逝 不值得挂心
Human lives are fleeting, they're nothing.
你该好好珍惜眼前人
You'd be better served by what lies in front of you.
我说这话 不是以众神之父的身份
I'm telling you this not as the All-father,
而是以父亲的身份
but as your father.
你准备好了 该接掌王位了
You are ready, the time has come for you to take the throne.
去享受庆祝你的胜利吧
Embrace and celebrate what you've won.
与你的将士一起
Join your warriors,
美酒佳肴 举杯同庆
eat and drink, revel in their celebration.
至少也装出点开心的样子
At least pretend to enjoy yourself.
再来
Another.
你以前会欢庆上好几个星期呢
There was a time when you would celebrate for weeks.
我记得海拉根一战后 你兴致高昂
I remember you celebrated the Battle of Harokin
差点挑起了第二次战役
so much that you nearly started the second.
谁让第一仗那么过瘾呢
Well, the first was so much fun.
跟我喝一杯吧
Take a drink with me.
众神之父今晚不会再派任务给你了吧
Surely the All-father could have no further task for you tonight.
对 可我给自己派了任务
No, this is one I set myself.
我注意到你每晚都会消失
It does not go unnoticed that you disappear each night.
世间有九大王国
There are Nine Realms,
阿斯加德未来的国王不能只盯着其中一个
the future king of Asgard must focus on more than one.
谢谢你的英勇与谏言 尊贵的希芙小姐
I thank you for your sword and for your counsel, good Lady Sif.
伦 敦
你有什么放不下的事
So what's the story with you?
为什么非得有事 我没什么放不下的事
Why does there have to be a story, there's no story.
我们约会的前十分钟里
You spent the first ten minutes of our date
你都躲在一份只有三道菜的菜单后面
hiding behind a menu that has three choices on it.
你能选的就只有鸡肉 蔬菜或鱼 简
It's either chicken, vegetarian or fish, Jane.
我猜你有放不下的事
I think there's a story
而那件事是有关一个男人的 对吗
and I'm thinking the story involves a guy?
一言难尽
It's complicated.
他还在你身边吗
Is he still around?
不 他
No, he...
走了
went away.
我也经历过
I've been there.
心爱的人离开是很痛苦的事 不是吗
The going away. It's hard, isn't it?
我以前交往过一个女人 她去纽约工作了
I was seeing a woman and uh...she took a job in New York,
最终感情敌不过距离
eventually the distance killed it.
还有就是…
And...and the fact that she uh...
她一直跟别的男人上床
she kept sleeping with other dudes.
- 不是吧 - 好多呢
- No! - Oh, so many.
你好 能给我们上点红酒吗
Hi. Um...could we get some wine please?
好啊 我也想来点
Sure, I'd love some.
理查德 这是达西
Richard, this is Darcy.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
你好
Oh, hello.
我去了实验室也就是你妈家
So, I show up to work at the lab/your mom's house,
满心以为会看到你穿着睡衣在屋里晃悠
fully expecting you to be moping around in your pajamas
吃着冰激凌 念念不忘…那个谁
eating ice cream obsessing about... you know who...
可你居然没有 你穿上了淑女装
But you're not! You're wearing lady clothes,
甚至还洗了澡 对吧 香喷喷的
you even showered, didn't you? You smell good.
有什么事
Is there a point to all this,
你跑到这儿来找我一定有什么要紧事
because there really needs to be a point to all this.
对
Right.
还记得你被你丢在一边的科学仪器吗
You know all that scientific equipment you don't look at anymore?
你现在得开始看了
You might wanna start looking at it again.
我们大老远跑来就是为了这个
This is the reason we came all the way out here.
出故障了
It's malfunctioning.
我也这么觉得
That's what I said.
我也这么做的
That's what I did!
还以为你做事会更科学点
I thought you'd do something a little more scientific.
- 应该没什么问题 - 嗯…
- I'm sure it's nothing. - Yeah, it's...
看起来不像没问题
It doesn't look like nothing.
有点像艾瑞克之前念叨的那些读数
Kind of looks like the readings that Erik was rambling about.
我们的朋友艾瑞克 他有点疯了
Our friend Erik, kind of went banana-balls.
他没兴趣
He's not interested.
- 我有兴趣 - 我也没兴趣
- I'm interested. - I'm not interested.
你可以走了
It's time for you to go now.
好吧
Okay.
短暂但愉快
Short but sweet.
她该吃药了
She needs help.
我还是点份鲈鱼吧
I think I'm gonna have the sea bass.
鲈鱼 嗯 鲈鱼不错
Sea bass. Yeah, sea bass is good.
鲈鱼 鲈鱼 鲈鱼 鲈鱼
Sea bass, sea bass, sea bass, sea bass,
鲈鱼 鲈鱼 鲈鱼 鲈鱼…
sea bass, sea bass, sea bass...sea bass. Sea bass...
- 鲈鱼 - 简
- Sea bass. - Jane,
你还是别念叨鲈鱼了
maybe you should stop saying "sea bass"
跟你朋友走吧
and go after your friend.
午餐很愉快
This was so fun.
我就自己在这儿念叨鲈鱼吧
You know, I'll just stay here and say "Sea bass" alone.
我恨你
And I hate you.
怎么了 我都夸他了
What?! I said he was cute.
你还是闭嘴开车吧
Just shut up and drive.
下个路口左转
You need to take the next left.
他是谁
Who's he?
他是我的实习生
He's my intern.
你都有实习生了
You have an intern?
没错
Oh, yeah.
你好 福斯特博士
Hello, Dr. Foster. It's uh...
能与你共事真是太荣幸了
It's such a great honor to be working with you.
好吧 我得打给艾瑞克
Right. I need to call Erik.
右转
Oh, uh...take a right.
再左转
And a left.
在伦敦开车我已经驾轻就熟了
I have totally mastered driving in London.
喂 艾瑞克 还是我 你在哪
Hi, Erik, it's me again. Where are you?
我过来是因为你说你有发现
I came here because you said you were onto something
结果你却消失了
and then you vanish.
我现在在巨石阵
I'm here at Stonehenge,
对今天发生的一则趣闻进行跟踪报道
for what has been an interesting unfolding of events today.
警方于今天上午11点刚过时
The police were called to the scene
接到报警 赶到现场
shortly after 11 a.m. this morning,
一名看似正常的男游客来到这里
after a seemingly harmless rambler approached the area
随即开始裸奔
then, decided to strip naked
并举着科学仪器 吓坏了游客
and effectively terrorize tourists there with scientific equipment
嘴里喊着他是想救他们
while shouting that he was trying to save them.
此人随后被证实为著名天文物理学家
The man later identified as noted astrophysicist
艾瑞克·塞尔维格博士
Dr. Erik Selvig
他目前已被警方拘留待审
has been called in for questioning by police.
快走 多令人激动啊
Come on, this is exciting!
看 实习生都激动了
Look, the intern is excited.
我叫伊恩
"Ian".
要带上相位表吗
Do you want the phase meter?
- 不要 - 拿上相位表
- No. - Bring the phase meter.
长得像面包机的那个
The toaster-looking thing.
我知道相位表长什么样
Yeah. I know what the phase meter is.
这手机的铃声要怎么换
How do I change the ringtone on this thing?
有三个学位的天文物理学家
An astrophysicist with three degrees
应该会自己换铃声
should be able to change her own ringtone.
为什么要打电话
Why are you calling me?
我不想大喊大叫
I didn't want to shout.
实习生说往这边走
Intern says it's this way.
伊恩 我叫伊恩
"Ian". My name is Ian.
我可不想因为搞个科学被人捅死
I am not getting stabbed in the name of science.
没事的 我们是美国人
It's okay, we're Americans!
这样说他们就会喜欢我们了吗
Is that supposed to make them like us?
他们能把它弄走
They'll make it go away.
只是孩子
Oh, they're kids.
你们是警察吗
Are you the police?
不 我们是科学家 我是
No, we're scientists. Well, I am.
- 谢谢 - 我们无意中发现的
- Thanks. - We just found it.
能带我们去看看吗
Can you show us?
这可不太正常
That doesn't seem right.
去哪了
Where'd it go?
这真是…
That's...
太不可思议了
that's incredible.
怎么回事
What happened?
有时候能回来 有时候回不来
Sometimes they come back, sometimes they don't.
我也想丢个东西 简 把你的鞋给我
I want to throw something. Jane, give me your shoe.
我上次见到这样的读数还是在…
I haven't seen readings like this since...
在…
since...
新墨西哥吗
New Mexico?
什么都别碰
Don't touch anything!
把你的鞋给我
Give me your shoe.
那是车钥匙吗
Were those the car keys?
达西
Darcy!
以太粒子唤醒了我们
天体汇聚又开始了
你来迟了
You're late.
有时欢庆比战斗更累人
Merriment can sometimes be a heavier burden than battle.
那你一定有一样没做对
Then you're doing one of them incorrectly.
也许吧
Perhaps.
繁星都还好吗
How fare the stars?
一如既往地闪烁着
Still shining.
我在这儿能看到九个王国和亿万生灵
From here I can see nine realms and ten trillion souls.
记得我跟你说过的天体汇聚吗
Do you recall what I told you of the Convergence?
记得 各个王国连成一线
Yes, the alignment of the worlds.
快要到来了 是吗
It approaches, doesn't it?
这宇宙奇观上一次出现
The universe hasn't seen this marvel
是在我守卫开始之前了
since before my watch began.
很少有人能感觉到 能看到的更少了
Few can sense it, even fewer can see it.
虽然它可能带来危险
But while its effects can be dangerous,
但真是美极了
it is truly beautiful.
我什么也看不到
I see nothing.
也许是因为那不是你想看的美景
Or perhaps that is not the beauty you seek.
她怎么样
How is she?
你的凡人还挺聪明
She's quite clever, your mortal.
她自己还不知道
She doesn't know it yet,
但她也在研究天体汇聚
but she studies the Convergence as well.
甚至…
Even...
怎么了
What?
我看不到她了
I can't see her.
简
Jane!
你去哪了啊
Where the hell were you?
你不会报警了吧
Tell me you didn't call the police!
不然我该怎么办
What was I supposed to do?
别报警啊
Not call the police!
我急疯了
I was freaking out.
你报警 警察就会通知联调局
You call the cops, they tell the Feds,
紧接着神盾局就从天而降
the next thing you know we have S.H.I.E.L.D crawling all over,
把这里变成51区
"Area 51-ing" the place.
- 简 - 我们发现了一个稳定的重力异常场
- Jane! - We had a stable gratification anomaly,
并且能自由进行研究
We had unimpeded access.
我们唯一的竞争对手是十岁的孩子
Our only competition was ten years old!
简 你失踪了五个小时
Jane, you were gone for five hours!
什么
What?
好诡异
That's weird.
总这样
Typical.
简
Jane.
抱歉 我必须确认下你是真的
Sorry. I just needed to make sure you were real,
今天真的好诡异
it's been a very strange day.
我是真的 简
Well, I am. Jane what...
你去哪了
Where were you?!
你又去哪了
Where were you?
海姆达尔看不到你
Heimdall could not see you.
我一直在原地等你
I was right here where you left me.
我一直在等你 后来我哭了
I was waiting and then I was crying
再后来我到处去找你
and then I went out looking for you.
你说你会回来的
You said you were coming back.
我知道 但是彩虹桥被毁了
I know, I know, but the Bifrost was destroyed.
九大王国爆发了战乱
The Nine Realms erupted into chaos,
战争肆虐 劫盗成群
wars were raging, marauders were pillaging.
我必须制止杀戮
I had to put an end to the slaughter.
这个理由倒是不坏
As excuses go, it's not terrible.
但我在电视上看见你了 你去了纽约啊
But I saw you on TV, you were...you were in New York!
简 我那时努力保护你不受来自我的世界的侵害
Jane, I fought to protect you from the dangers of my world,
但我错了 我太傻了
but I was wrong, I was a fool.
我相信是命运让我们走到一起
But I believe that fate brought us together.
简 我不知道你去了哪 发生了什么事
Jane, I don't know where you were or what happened,
但我很清楚一件事
but I do know this.
什么
What?
我知道
I know...
真的知道吗
You do?
知道什么
Do what?
什么
What?
是你干的吗
Is this you?
我们有点事要忙
Uh...we're kind of in the middle of something here.
我确定我们要被捕了
Um...I'm pretty sure we are getting arrested.
等一下
Hold that thought.
看看你
Look at you!
还是那么肌肉发达 宇宙怎么样
Still all muscly and everything. How's space?
挺好的
Space is fine.
打扰一下
Excuse me?
- 你是简·福斯特吗 - 是的
- Are you Jane Foster? - Yes.
你认识这个人吗
Do you know this man?
他是我的实习生
He's my intern.
我实习生的实习生
My intern's intern.
这里是私人领地
This is private property
你们全都涉嫌非法入侵
and you're trespassing, the lot of you.
请你跟我们走一趟
You'll have to come with me.
简
Jane!
Jane?
托尔
Thor.
你没事吧
You alright?
刚刚怎么回事
What just happened?
把手放在头上 退后
Place your hands on your heads, step back!
这位女士不舒服
This woman is unwell.
她很危险
She's dangerous.
我也是
So am I.
请求武警速到现场支援
Requesting armed response officers to the scene.
抱紧我
Hold on to me.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
我去
Holy shit!
我们得再来一次
We have to do that again.
欢迎来到阿斯加德
Welcome to Asgard.
瓦特海姆
瞧瞧我留下了什么 阿格姆
我几乎记不清光明之前的日子了
我们种族的延续将是你留给后世的遗产
我要让阿斯加德人尝尽我们吃的苦头
我要拿回以太粒子
我要恢复我们的世界
我要终结这饱受荼毒的宇宙
这是什么
What's that?
别动
Be still.
这不是地球上的物质 它是什么
This is not of Earth, what is it?
还不清楚
We do not know.
但她体内涌动的能量太大 她撑不住的
But she will not survive the amount of energy surging within her.
这是量子场发生器 对吗
That's a quantum field generator, isn't it?
这是灵魂冶炼炉
It's a Soul Forge.
灵魂冶炼炉能迁移分子能吗
Does a Soul Forge transfer molecular energy from one place to another?
是的
Yes.
就是量子场发生器
Quantum field generator.
我的话对你来说只是耳旁风吗
My words are mere noises to you that you ignore them completely?
她病了
She's ill.
她是凡人
She is mortal.
他们都会患病
Illness is their defining trait.
我带她来是因为我们能救她
I brought her here because we can help her.
她不属于阿斯加德
She does not belong here in Asgard
如同山羊肉上不了宴会台面一样
anymore than a goat belongs at a banquet table.
他刚刚是说…
Did he just...?
你以为你是谁啊
Who do you think you are?
我是奥丁 阿斯加德国王
I'm Odin. King of Asgard.
九大王国的保护者
Protector of the Nine Realms.
我是…
Oh. Well, I'm...
我很清楚你是谁 简·福斯特
I know very well who you are, Jane Foster.
你跟你爸提过我
You told your dad about me?
她体内有一些物质 父王
Something is within her, father,
我从没见过的物质
something I have not seen before.
她的星球有自己的治疗师 他们叫医生
Her world has its healers. They are called "doctors."
交给他们处理吧
Let them deal with it.
守卫 送她回米德加德
Guards, take her back to Midgard.
不 不要
No, I wouldn't...
碰她
...touch her.
简 你没事吧
Jane, are you alright?
这不可能
It's impossible.
她感染的东西在保护她
The infection, it's defending her.
不
No,
是在保护它自己
it's defending itself.
跟我来
Come with me.
有些东西的历史可以追溯到宇宙成形之前
There are relics that predate the universe itself.
她体内的东西 似乎就是这样的古物
What lies within her appears to be one of them.
九大王国并非永恒的
The Nine Realms are not eternal.
他们有诞生的黎明 也将有坍圮的黄昏
They had a dawn as they will have a dusk.
但在那黎明之前 黑暗势力
But before that dawn the dark forces,
黑暗精灵 独霸宇宙
the Dark Elves, reigned absolute
无人匹敌
and unchallenged.
诞自永恒之夜
"Born of eternal night,
黑暗精灵将盗走你的光明
the Dark Elves comes to steal away your light."
小时候母后跟我们讲过他们的故事
They were these stories mother told them to us as children.
他们的首领 马勒基斯
Their leader, Malekith
用那黑暗创造了一个武器
made a weapon out of that darkness,
叫做以太粒子
and it was called the Aether.
其他古物大都是固体
While the other relics often appeared as stones,
以太粒子却是不停变化的流体
the Aether is fluid and everchanging.
它能将物体变成暗物质
It changes matter into dark matter,
它寻找寄主寄生
it seeks out to host bodies,
并汲取寄主的生命力
drawing strength from their life force.
马勒基斯想利用以太的能量
Malekith sought to use the Aether's power
让宇宙重归黑暗
to return the universe to one of darkness.
但历经了漫长的血战
But after eternities of blood shed,
我父王包尔 终于取胜
my father Bor, finally triumphed,
从此开启了数千年的和平
ushering in the peace that lasted thousands of years.
怎么个取胜法
What happened?
他消灭了黑暗精灵
He killed them all.
您确定吗
Are you certain?
传说以太粒子跟他们一同被摧毁
The Aether was said to have been destroyed with them
但如今却又出现
and yet here it is.
黑暗精灵已经灭绝
The Dark Elves are dead.
书上提到怎么把它从我身体里取出来吗
Does your book happen to mention how to get it out of me?
没有
No, it does not.
天体汇聚即将形成
你将是最后一个诅咒战士
我愿牺牲自己
就像我们的人民
和你那样
你将成为黑暗
并维持这一形态 直到它耗尽你的生命
在那之前 我们的敌人将不是你的对手
我将摧毁他们的防线 让你回到一个崭新的宇宙中
看管这些无赖真是有失我们的身份
Acting as caretakers to these scoundrels is beneath us.
拜托
Oh, please.
如果他们压在了你的身下 我壮硕的朋友
If they were beneath you my rotund friend,
他们肯定要没命了
they'd all be dead.
不要出队
Keep in line.
往前走
Move it!
奥丁总给我送新朋友来
Odin continues to bring me new friends.
真周到啊
How thoughtful.
我送来的书 你不喜欢吗
The books I sent, do they not interest you?
我就这么打发余生吗 读书
Is that how I'm to wile away eternity, reading?
我已经尽力让你过得舒坦些 洛基
I've done everything in my power to make you comfortable, Loki.
是嘛
Have you?
奥丁也会操这份心吗
Does Odin share your concern?
托尔呢
Does Thor?
他们如此日夜挂念我 一定很操劳啊
It must be so inconvenient them asking after me day and night.
你很清楚 你落得这个下场完全是咎由自取
You know full well it was your actions that brought you here.
咎由自取
My actions.
你们一直骗我说我生来就该为王
I was merely giving truth to the lie
我不过是将这个谎言
that I've been fed my entire life,
变成了现实
that I was born to be a king.
为王
A king?
真正的国王会承认错误
A true king admits his faults.
你在地球大开杀戒要怎么说
What of the lives you took on Earth?
跟奥丁杀过的人相比简直九牛一毛
A mere handful compared to the number Odin has taken himself.
你父亲
Your father...
他不是我父亲
He's not my father!
那我也不是你母亲吗
Then am I not your mother?
不是
You're not.
你总能看透一切 却看不透自己
You're always so perceptive about everyone but yourself.
你去找我的时候就知道我有麻烦了吗
When you came for me, you knew I was in trouble.
海姆达尔看不到你时 你就不在地球上了
When Heimdall had lost sight of you, you were no longer on Earth.
这怎么可能啊
Well, how's that possible?
我认为你既在又不在
I believe you were and you weren't.
九大王国在宇宙树中游走
The Nine Realms travel within Yggdrasil,
像地球环绕太阳那样环绕米德加德
orbiting Midgard in much the way your planet orbits the sun.
每五千年 这些王国列成一条直线
And every five thousand years the worlds align perfectly,
我们称之为天体汇聚
and we call this the Convergence.
在此期间 各王国间的界线会变得模糊
During this time the boarders between worlds become blurred.
你可能就是找到了这样一个模糊点
It's possible you found one of these points.
那个点没有关闭真是走运
We are lucky that it remained open.
一旦各王国偏离汇聚直线
Once the worlds pass out of alignment,
与彼此的连接就会中断
the connection is lost.
我喜欢你解释的方式
I liked the way you explained things.
我会怎么样
What's gonna happen to me?
我会想办法救你的 简
I'll find a way to save you, Jane.
你父亲说没办法…
Your father said there was...
我父亲也并非无所不知
My father doesn't know everything.
可别让他听见你说这话
Don't let him hear you say that.
简·福斯特 这位是弗丽嘉
Jane Foster, please meet Frigga,
阿斯加德的王后 我母亲
Queen of Asgard, my mother.
快走
Move!
快去地牢
To the dungeons!
快走
Come on!
走左边的楼梯吧
You might want to take the stairs to the left.
是监狱
The prisons.
洛基
Loki.
去吧 我会照顾她
Go, I will look after her.
他们简直像是讨厌被囚禁
It is as if they resented being imprisoned.
有些家伙就是不知足
There's no pleasing some creatures.
回牢房去 事后概不追究
Return to your cells, no further harm will come to you.
我保证
You have my word.
好吧 我收回
Very well, you do not have my word.
派一队人去武器库
Send a squadron to the weapons vault,
不惜一切代价保卫那里 守住地牢
defend it at all costs. Secure the dungeon.
奥丁
Odin.
弗丽嘉
Frigga.
去啊
Go!
就是点小乱子 不用担心
It's a skirmish, nothing to fear.
你一向不会撒谎
You've never been a very good liar.
带她去你房里 等安全了我会去找你
Take her to you chambers, I'll come for you when it's safe.
你小心
You take care.
历经了多少风风雨雨
Despite all I have survived,
我的王后还是会担心我
my queen still worries over me.
就是因为我担心 你才能逢凶化吉
It's only because I worry over you that you have survived.
听好了
Listen to me now,
你要完全照我说的做 不许多问
I need you to do everything I ask and no questions.
是 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
阿斯加德的王座被毁了 去保护国王
The throne of Asgard is destroyed! To the king!
弗丽嘉
Frigga.
退下 怪物
Stand down, creature.
我尚可饶你一命
And you may still survive this.
我命大得很呢 女人
I have survive worse, woman.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是马勒基斯
I am Malekith.
我要拿回我的东西
And I would have what is mine.
你拿走了一样东西 孩子
You have taken something, child.
还给我
Give it back.
女巫
Witch.
以太粒子在哪
Where is the Aether.
我绝不会告诉你
I'll never tell you.
这我相信
I believe you.
不
No.
宇宙五千年一个循环
The universe rotates on a five thousand years cycle.
每轮循环中会有一次 各个世界排列成直线
And once a cycle, all the worlds align.
把这个想象成我们的世界
Imagine... imagine that this is our world,
谢谢
oh, thank you,
这是另一个世界
and this is another world,
一般来说 他们彼此分开
normally, they're seperate.
但世界汇聚时
But during the Alignment,
一切都彼此相连
everything is connected,
九大王国都在穿过彼此
all nine realms. All nine realms are passing through each other,
重力 光 甚至物质
and gravity, light, and even matter
都会从一个世界挤进另一个世界
is crushing from one world to the other.
如果这一切现在发生 后果将是毁灭性的
But if this happens to us now, the result could be cataclysmic.
我的重力测量仪能稳定
My gravimetric-spikes can stablize
天体汇聚的界点
the focus point of the Convergance.
这样 其他世界
This time, the Alignment
和他们的纵列就会跟我们擦肩而过
and all the other worlds would just pass us by.
太妙了
It's beautiful.
也很简单
Simple.
有什么问题吗
Any questions?
有 能把我的鞋还给我吗
Yeah, can I have my shoe back?
恢复吧 夺回以太粒子 你需要力气
等你醒来 我们去把他们赶尽杀绝
简·福斯特
Jane Foster?
你得跟我们来
You need to come with us.
我们依然无法恢复王宫的屏障
We are still unable to restore the palace shields.
我们的大炮探测不到他们
Our artillery cannot detect them,
海姆达尔都看不到他们
even Heimdall cannot see them.
陛下
My king,
我们完全失去了防御能力
we're all but defenseless.
你把她囚禁起来了
She's your prisoner now?
都退下
Leave us.
我不想跟你争论
I do not wish to fight with you.
我也不想跟您争论
Nor I with you.
但我想去追击马勒基斯
But I intended to pursue Malekith.
以太粒子在我们手上
We possess the Aether.
马勒基斯会送上门来
Malekith will come to us.
没错 他会摧毁我们
Yes, and he will destroy us.
你高估了这些怪物
You overestimate the power of these creatures.
不 我只是珍惜我们人民的生命
No, I value our people's lives.
我带简去黑暗世界
I'll take Jane to the Dark World,
将敌人从阿斯加德引开
and draw the enemies away from Asgard.
马勒基斯把以太粒子从简身体里取出时
When Malekith pulls the Aether from Jane,
它会暴露在外 不堪一击
it would be exposed and vulnerable.
我到时就把他们一同消灭
And I would destroy it and him.
你这是冒险
If you fail,
一旦失败 武器就会落入敌手
you risk this weapon falling into the hands of our enemie.
如果我们坐以待毙只会更危险
The risk is far greater if we do nothing.
他的舰队可能此刻就在我们头上盘旋
His ships could be over our heads right now,
我们根本无从知道
we would never even know.
等他来了
If and when he comes,
他的手下会败在数万阿斯加德士兵的兵刃下
his men will fall on ten thousand Asgardian blades.
那我们又要牺牲多少人呢
And how many our men should fall on theirs?
牺牲多少都在所不惜
As many as I need it.
我们会坚持战斗
We will fight
坚持到最后一个阿斯加德人
till the last Asgardian breath,
坚持到阿斯加德人鲜血流尽
till the last drop of Asgardian blood.
那您跟马勒基斯又有何区别
Then how are you different from Malekith?
我的儿子 区别在于 我终将胜利
The different, my son, is that I will win.
简不回我电话
Jane isn't calling me back.
艾瑞克不回我电话
Erik isn't calling me Back.
神盾局也不回我电话
Stupid S.H.I.E.L.D isn't calling me back.
神盾局是什么
What's S.H.I.E.L.D?
是秘密
It's a secret.
艾瑞克 又是达西
Hi, Erik, it's Darcy again.
托尔回来了
Thor came back,
他把简带去了阿斯加德
he took Jane to Asgard.
我也不知道该怎么办才好
And I'm not sure what I'm suppose to do.
这周还有人丢了点什么
Something else went missing this week,
天体物理学家 艾瑞克·塞尔维格博士
when astrophysicist Dr. Erik Selvig
因卷入纽约外星人入侵事件
notable for his involvement in the alien invasion
而为人所知
of New York.
- 裸奔在… - 达西 你得看看这个
- Stripped nude... - Darcy, you really need to look at this.
你的朋友艾瑞克
Your friend Erik,
他姓什么来着
what was his last name again?
并对该历史景点的游客大吼大叫
...and began shouting at visitors to the historic site.
随后他被警方拘留
He was later taken into police custody
以待精神鉴定
for psychiatric evaluation.
警方仍然不肯证实…
The police is still refusing to confirm...
你没去参加奥丁的军事会议
You were not at Odin's war council.
你父王下令关闭彩虹桥
The Bifrost is closed by your father's orders.
任何人不得进出阿斯加德
No one was to come, or to go.
连我都看不见敌人
We face an enemy that is invisible even to me,
那么
what use
我这个守护者还有何用
is a guardian such as that.
马勒基斯还会回来的 这你很清楚
Malekith will return. You know this.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我不能违抗国王的命令
I cannot overrule my king's wishes.
即便是为你
Not even for you.
我没有这个意思
I'm not asking you to.
九大王国需要一个坚强 服众的众神之父
The realms need their All-father strong and unchallenged,
不论情况是否如此
whether he is or not.
但他看不清现实 海姆达尔
But he's binded Heimdall,
仇恨和悲伤蒙蔽了他
by hatred and by grief.
我们不都是吗
As are we all.
我看得很清楚
I see clearly enough.
风险太大了
The risks are to great.
从现在起 我们走的每一步都有风险
Everything we do from here on is a risk.
我们别无选择
There is no other way.
你要我怎么做
What do you require of me.
我要你们做的事 是最严重的叛国罪
What I'm about to ask you is treason of the highest order.
即便成功 我们也将被流放
Success will bring us exile,
而失败则必死无疑
and failure shall mean our death.
马勒基斯知道以太粒子在这儿
Malekith knew the Aether was here.
他能感应它的能量
He can sense its power.
如果不采取行动 他会再次攻来
If we do nothing, he'll come for it again,
但这次 他们将彻底摧毁阿斯加德
but this time, lay waste to all of Asgard.
我们得带简离开这儿
We must move Jane off world.
彩虹桥已经关闭
The Bifrost has been shut down,
宇宙魔方也锁在地下室里
and the Tesseract locked away in the vault.
离开阿斯加德还有其他途径
There are other path off Asgard,
了解这些途径的人为数不多
ways known only to a few.
准确说只有一个
One actually.
不会吧
No.
托尔
Thor.
都这么久了
After all this time,
你现在来看我
now you come to visit me,
来干什么
why?
幸灾乐祸吗
Have you come to gloat?
嘲笑我
To mock?
洛基 够了
Loki enough.
别再用幻象了
No more illusions.
现在你看到我了 哥哥
Now you see me brother.
她走得痛苦吗
Did she suffer?
我不是来跟你一同哀悼母亲的
I did not come here to share our grief.
我是来给你机会得到一样更好的东西
Instead I offer you the chance of a far richer sacrament.
说
Go on.
我知道你跟我一样想复仇
I know you seek vengeance as much as I do.
你帮我逃出阿斯加德 我就给你机会
You help me escape Asgard and I will grant it to you.
让你复仇
Vengeance.
然后再回这儿来
And afterwards this cell.
你一定是走投无路了 才会来找我帮忙
You must be truely desperate to come to me for help.
你凭什么觉得你能信任我
What makes you think you can trust me.
我不信任
I don't.
母亲信任你
Mother did.
但你要知道 过去我们交手的时候
But you should know that when we fought each other in the past,
我仍然抱有一丝希望
I did so with a glimpse of hope
相信我弟弟还没完全消失
that my brother was still in there somewhere.
这一丝希望已经幻灭 不能再保护你了
That hope is no longer exist to protect you.
你敢背叛我 我就杀了你
You betray me, and I will kill you.
什么时候出发
When do we start?
他肯定会背叛你的
He will betray you.
让他试试看
He will try.
这太不像你了 哥哥
This is so unlike you, brother.
这样秘密行动
So clandestine.
你真的不想靠蛮力打出一条血路出去吗
Are you sure you wouldn't rather just punch your way out.
你再不闭嘴我就要动手了
If you keep speaking I just might.
好吧 听你的
Fine, as you wish,
我都不在这儿
I'm not even here.
这样好点了吧
Is this better?
比你本人强多了
It's better company at least.
不过 我们还可以再低调点
Still, we could be less conspicuous.
哥哥
Umm, brother,
你可真美
you look ravishing.
就算变成这样 我照样能让你死得很惨
It will hurt no less when I kill you in this form.
好吧
Very well.
或许你想要你新结交的小伙伴
Perhaps you prefer one of your new companions,
毕竟你似乎很喜欢他们
given that you seem to like them so much.
这样好多了呢
Oh this is much better.
服装不太合身
The costume is bit much.
太紧了
So tight.
但那股自信
But the confidence,
我能感到正义在我身体里涌动
I can feel the righteousness surging.
想跟我畅谈一下真理吗
Hey, do you wanna have a rousing discussion about truth?
或是荣誉
Honor?
爱国主义
Patriotism?
天佑美国…
God bless America...
干什么
What?
你至少也该给我件武器啊
You could at least furnish me with a weapon.
我的匕首什么的
My dagger, something.
这才对嘛
At last,
总算讲点理了
a little common sense.
你不就喜欢小戏法吗
And I thought you like tricks.
然后呢
Well, what then?
你心爱的凡人被一整队英灵战士看守着
Your lovely mortal is been guarded by a legion of Einherjar
他们大老远就能看到你
who will see you coming from miles away.
去接她的不是我
I won't be the one who comes for her.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
那正好 我们走
Good, let's go.
是你…
You're...
我是洛基 你可能听说过我
I'm Loki, you may have heard of me.
这一掌是为了纽约
That was for New York.
我喜欢她
I like her.
那众神之父呢
And what of the All-Father?
我曾立誓向他通报一切叛国罪行
It is my sworn duty to notify him of crimes against the throne.
你要我过来
You called me here
说是有紧急情况
on urgent matter.
是什么事
What is it?
有人叛国犯上 陛下
Treason, my lord.
是谁
Whose?
我
Mine.
陛下
My king,
那个凡人被劫走了
the mortal has been taken.
阻止托尔
Stop Thor,
不惜一切代价
by any means necessary.
他们在那儿 抓住他们
There they are! Take them.
听我命令
On my command.
我拖住他们 带她走
I'll hold them off. Take her.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你敢背叛他
Betray him,
我就杀了你
and I'll kill you.
我也很高兴见到你 希芙
It's good to see you, too, Sif.
就算洛基肯帮你 你也救出了那个凡人
Assuming you can get Loki's help and you can free this mortal,
又有什么用啊
what good would it do?
我们踏出宫殿一步 就必死无疑
We'd all be dead the minute we step one foot outside the palace.
所以 我的朋友 我们不会步行离开
That, my friend, is why we won't be leaving by foot.
我尽量帮你拖延时间
I will give you as much time as I can.
谢谢你 我的朋友
Thank you, my friend.
你胆敢打背叛他的主意
If you even think of betraying him.
你就杀了我吗
You'll kill me?
看来你得排队了
Evidently there will be a line.
你不是说你会驾驶这东西吗
I thought you said you knew how to fly this thing.
我是说这能有多难
I said "How hard could it be".
他们在飞船上
They're on the ship.
拦住飞船
Get to the ship.
不管你在做什么 哥哥 你得快点了
Well, whatever you're doing brother, I suggest you do it faster.
闭嘴 洛基
Shut up, Loki.
你肯定漏掉什么了
You must have missed something.
我没有 我把这上面的按钮都按遍了
No, I didn't, I'm pressing every button on this thing.
别用力那么猛 轻轻按
No. Don't hit it, just press it gently.
我在轻轻按了 不好使
I am pressing it gently, it's not working.
擒住他 拿下他
Get him! Get him!
还有根柱子没撞到呢
I think you missed a column.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你为什么不让我来呢
Look, why don't you let me take over,
我的驾驶技术显然更好
I'm clearly the best pilot.
是嘛
Is that right?
我们两个人中 谁才是会飞的那个
Well, out of the two of us, which one can actually fly?
天啊 她死了吗
Oh dear, is she dead?
简
Jane.
我没事
I'm okay.
别多嘴
Not a word.
他们跟上来了
Now they're following us.
他们开火了
Now they're firing at us.
多谢你的解说 洛基
Yeah, thank you for the commentary Loki,
完全不会让人分心
it's not at all distracting.
干得漂亮 你把你爷爷的头砍下来了
Well done, you just decapitated your grandfather.
这真是太棒了
You know this is wonderful,
这主意真是了不起
this is a tremendous idea.
我们去把宇宙中最大最显眼的飞船偷来
Let's steal the biggest, most obvious ship in the universe,
乘着它逃跑
and escape in that.
驾着它满城乱飞
Flying around the city,
看见什么撞什么 让大家都看见我们
smashing into everything in sight, so everyone can see us.
太聪明了 托尔
It's brilliant, Thor.
真有你的
It's truly brilliant.
在牢里关了那么久
I see your time in the dungeons
你还是这么优雅啊 洛基
has make you no less graceful, Loki.
你骗我
You lied to me.
挺厉害啊
I'm impressed.
你满意我很高兴
I'm glad you're pleased.
遵守你的承诺吧
Now do as you promised.
带我们去你的秘密通道
And take us to your secret pathway.
范达尔
Fandral.
好的
Right.
为了阿斯加德
For Asgard.
别往心里去啊 伙计们
Nothing personal, boys.
洛基
Loki.
如果那么容易
If it were easy,
谁都能做到了
everyone would do it.
你疯了吗
Are you mad?
或许吧
Possibly.
胜利到达
Ta-da.
我们得马上出击
不
不必去阿斯加德了
以太自己送上门了
那能量要是给我 我能做多少事啊
What I could do with the power that flows through those veins.
你会被吞噬的
It would consume you.
她不就没事
She's holding up all right
暂时没事
For now.
她拥有的力量你无法理解
She's strong in ways you'd never even know.
道别吧
Say goodbye.
不会是今天
Not this day.
今天 明天
This day, the next,
一百年 算什么
a hundred years, is nothing,
弹指一挥间而已
it's a heartbeat.
你永远放不开手
You'll never be ready.
你唯一珍视的挚爱终将被岁月夺去
The only woman whose love you've prized will be snatched from you.
那样你就满足了吗
And will that satisfy you.
我永远不会满足
Satisfaction is not in my nature.
我永远不会放弃
Surrender is not in mine.
果然是奥丁之子
Son of Odin.
我不只是奥丁的儿子
No, not just of Odin.
你以为母亲只爱你吗
You think you alone were loved of Mother?
她把技艺教给了你 但她信任的是我
You had her tricks but I had her trust.
信任
Trust?
那是她的遗言吗
Was that her last expression?
她信任你
Trust?
你却眼睁睁看她遇害
When you let her die?
你在地牢里出手相救了吗
What help were you in your cell?
谁把我关进去的
Who put me there?
你心里清楚 你心里清楚是谁
You know damn well. You know damn well who.
她不会希望我们兄弟相争
She wouldn't want us to fight.
她都见怪不怪了吧
Well, she wouldn't exactly be shocked.
真希望我能相信你
I wish I can trust you.
相信我的怒火吧
Trust my rage.
塞尔维格先生 请签收您父亲的物品
You'll have to sign for your fathers' belongings Mr. Selvig.
什么
What?
啊对
Oh, yeah.
我父亲 艾瑞克·塞尔维格博士
My father Dr. Erik Selvig.
一个棕色男士钱包
One man's leather wallet, brown,
一串钥匙 共三把
one keyring, three keys,
处方药
prescription medicine,
若干
various.
- 还有 - 艾瑞克
- And, - Erik.
- 这些 - 对 这些
- These. - Yeah, those.
谢天谢地
Thank goodness.
艾瑞克
Erik.
嗯
Yes.
我是达西
It's...Darcy.
达西
Darcy.
见到你真高兴
So good to see you.
我也挺想你
I miss you too.
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
你在电视上裸奔了
You were naked on TV.
好了 该走了 还有事要做
Okay, it's time to go, lots to do.
越来越尴尬了
Getting weird now.
怎么能让我管这些事
I should not be left in charge of stuff like this,
又没人给我那么多钱
I don't get paid enough.
是根本没人给我钱
I don't get paid period.
那个 我叫伊恩 达西的实习生
I'm Ian, by the way, Darcy's inter.
也没人给我钱
Yeah, I don't get paid either.
你没事吧
Are you alright?
我脑子里有个神
I've had a god in my brain.
这滋味可不好受了
I don't recommend it.
塞尔维格博士 这设备响了
Dr. Selvig, sir, your gear is beeping.
果然开始了
It's happening.
比我计算得还早
It's sooner than I calculate.
什么开始了
Wait what's happening?
鸟吗
Birds?
鸟儿开始了
Birds are happening?
那是一群欧椋鸟
It's starling. It's called the murmuration.
小时候我爸常带我去观鸟
My dad, he used to take me bird watching as a kid.
呆子
Nerd.
看
Look.
他们去哪了
Where did they go?
刚刚怎么回事
What the hell was that?
你笑什么
Why are you smiling?
发现这世界比我还疯狂
There's nothing more reassuring than realize
我倍感安心
that the world is crazier than you are.
带我去简的实验室
Take me to Jane's lab.
简
Jane.
马勒基斯
Malekith.
准备好了吗
All right, are you ready?
我准备好了
I am.
你这破计划得把咱俩都害死
You know this plan of yours is gonna get us killed.
或许吧
Yeah, possibly.
你还不相信我吗 哥哥
You still don't trust me, brother?
你会相信你吗
Would you?
不会
No, I wouldn't.
托尔
Thor.
不
No.
你真以为我在乎弗丽嘉
You really think I cared about Frigga.
在乎你们任何人吗
About any of you.
我只渴望
All I ever wanted
看到你和奥丁
was you and Odin
死在我脚下
dead at my feet.
马勒基斯
Malekith.
我是约顿海姆的洛基
I am Loki of Jotunheim.
给你送来了大礼
And I bring you a gift.
我要的回报很简单
I ask only one thing in return.
让我看着阿斯加德化为灰烬
A good seat from which to watch Asgard burned.
他是阿斯加德的敌人
看着我
Look at me.
洛基 快
Loki, now!
不
No!
我们地狱见 怪物
See you in hell, monster.
不不不不
No, no, no, no...
- 你真傻 怎么不听我的 - 我知道
- You fool, you didn't listen. - I know.
我真傻
I'm a fool.
- 我真傻 - 挺住
- I'm a fool. - Stay with me. Okay?
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起 对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
没事的
It's okay.
It's all right.
你的英勇我会禀告父王
I'll tell father what you did here today.
我不是为了他
I didn't do it for him.
不
No!
他要释放以太
He's going to unleash it.
不只是在阿斯加德或是哪个星球
No just on Asgard or on a stars.
马勒基斯要毁灭一切
Malekith is gonna destroy everything.
怎么毁灭
How?
简 怎么毁灭
Jane, how?
我看到他在地球上 他去那儿干什么
I saw him on Earth. Why would he go to Earth?
天体汇聚
The Convergence.
天哪
Oh, God.
我要是没发现以太 就不会走到这一步了
None of this would have happened if I hadn't found the Aether.
马勒基斯只会更早得到以太
Then Malekith would've only possess that much sooner.
我是找你的时候发现了以太
I only found it because I was looking for you.
简
Jane.
结果困在这儿了
Now we're trapped here.
不是我
It's not me.
喂
Hello?
简 是我 理查德
Hi, Jane, it's Richard.
理查德 你在哪
Richard? Where are you?
还在办公室里 今天忙疯了
I'm still at the office, it's...it's been a crazy day here today.
天哪 太神奇了
Oh, my God, this is amazing.
是吗 跟你共进午餐很开心
Is it? I quite enjoy our lunch.
虽然什么都没点
Despite never actually ordering anything.
这地方怎么有信号
How am I getting service here?
现在不方便吗 要不我过会儿再打
Is it a bad time? Do you want me to try later?
不不 无论如何
No, no, no... please, whatever you do,
千万别挂电话
do not hang up the phone.
好吧
Okay then.
我就是想问你想不想再约一次
I was just wondering if you want to try again.
一起共进晚餐吧
Uh, maybe dinner next time.
好啊
Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
别挂电话 好吗
Just... stay on the phone, okay?
好呀
Yeah, I will.
天哪
Oh, my God.
你在忙吗
Am I interrupting something?
没 没有
No, no... nothing at all.
- 走吧 - 我听不清 你在隧道里吗
- Come on. - I'm losing you there, are you in tunnel?
怎么 这是去哪
What? Where are we going?
喂
Hello?
这里怎么这么多鞋
Why are there so many shoes in here?
还是发短信吧
I'll just text her.
理查德是谁
So who's Richard?
你不是吧
Really?
简
Jane.
你怎么说走就走 全世界都疯了
You can't just leave like that. The whole world is going crazy.
我们之前看到的异象到处都是了
All the stuff we saw is spreading.
你去参加派对了吗
Did you go to a party?
艾瑞克
Erik?
简
Jane.
太好了
How wonderful.
你去阿斯加德了
You've been to Asgard.
你的裤子呢
Where are your pants?
他说光着有助于思考
Oh, he says it helps him think.
你的研究成果都给我
Okay, well, I'm gonna need everything you got on this,
所有针对重力异常的研究
all the work you've been doing on gravimetric anomalies,
- 都给我 - 好吧
- everything. - Okay.
你还好吧 艾瑞克
Are you well, Erik?
你弟弟不来吧
Your brother's not coming, is he?
洛基死了
Loki is dead.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
那个 请节哀
I.. meant, I'm so sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
打扰了 陛下
Forgive me, my liege.
我从黑暗世界带来了消息
I've returned from the Dark World with news.
托尔吗
Thor?
没见到他
There was no sign of Thor.
也不见那个武器 但是
Or the weapon, but...
怎么了
What?
发现了具尸体
We found a body.
洛基
Loki.
马勒基斯要在
Malekith is going to fire the Aether
九大王国汇聚相连的地方发射以太
at the spot where all the nine worlds are connecting.
以增加以太的威力
Amplifying the weapon's impact.
威力随连通的王国数的增加呈指数增长
For each additional world, the power will increase exponentially.
足以波及整个宇宙
The effect would be universal.
但汇聚只会维持很短的时间
Yes, but the Alignment is only temperory,
他必须分秒不差地赶到正确地点
he must be in exactly the right place at the right time.
那正确地点是哪
Well, how do we know where that is?
沿着路标走
We follow the directions.
几千年前汇聚也曾发生过
This has happened before, thousands of years ago.
古人曾亲眼目睹
And the Ancients were there to see it.
那些了不起的古建筑工程
All the great constructions,
玛雅人 中国人 古埃及人
the Mayans, the Chinese, the Egyptians.
都曾利用汇聚对重力的影响
They made use of the gravitational affects of the Convergence.
这就是我们的地图
And they left us a map.
巨石阵
Stonehenge.
斯诺登山 大奥姆岬
Snowdon. Great Orme.
以他们为坐标 就能找到
These are all coordinates. Taking us...
这里
here.
格林威治
Greenwich.
九大王国之间的界限将几乎消失
The walls between worlds will almost non-existing,
物理学定律完全乱套
physics is gonna go ballistic.
重力忽增忽减
Increases and decreases of gravity,
空间挤压
spacial extrusions,
现实的世界在那里支离破碎
the very fabric of reality is gonna be torn apart.
我还是穿上裤子吧
I better get my pants.
集中精神 这可重要了
Focus, this is important.
我们得先把仪器钉在周围
We had to hammer them in all around the site,
然后简和艾瑞克会在塔上启动
and then Jane and Erik will activate them from the tower.
都绑在一起了
They're taped together.
你知道这仪器是干什么的吗
Do you even know what these things do?
不知道
No.
我也不知道
Neither do I.
- 快点 快点 - 好吧
- Come on, come on, come on. - Right.
我…
Holy
去
shit.
何必跑这么远 阿斯加德人
You needn't have come so far Asgardian.
死亡很快就要找上门了
Death would've come to you soon enough.
那也不是死在你手上
Not by your hand.
你们的宇宙就不该存在
Your universe was never meant to be.
你的王国 你的家人将被彻底消灭
Your world, and your family will be extinguished.
没时间了
We're running out of time.
快了
Almost there.
这真的能行吗
You sure this is gonna work.
这仪器是用来检测异常的 而不是引发异常
These devices were made to detect anomalies, not causing them.
快点
Come on.
快点 达西
Come on, Darcy.
你有那么强的力量
You know, with all that power,
出手怎么这么轻
I thought you'd hit harder.
好了
Done.
天体汇聚将于7分钟后达到最佳状态
The Convergences will be in full effect in 7 minutes.
那我们得拖住马勒基斯8分钟
That just means we have to keep Malekith busy for 8.
好了 你最好扶稳了
Okay, you might want to hold on to something.
太厉害了 你怎么办到的
That is awesome. How did you do that?
重力场与各王国之间的薄弱点相互作用
Well, gravitational fields interact with the weak spot between worlds...
- 产生了 - 干掉拿剑的那个
- creating... - Get the guy with the sword.
走吧
Let's go.
这是怎么回事
What the hell just happened?
快跑
Move!
你们干什么呢
What are you all doing?
赶快出去啊
You need to get out of here. Now.
你开玩笑呢
You're joking, right?
那可是雷神
That's Thor out there,
还拿着锤子挥来挥去
he's waving his hammer around and everything.
请确认是否为敌方飞船
Confirming ship is hostile.
确认为敌方飞船
Confirmed, ship is hostile.
可以开火
You have permission to engage.
收到 导弹锁定
Roger, missiles locked.
导弹已发射
Missiles away.
导弹偏离目标 重复 偏离目标
Missiles off target. I repeat, target missed.
我失去控制了 求救 求救
I'm losing control. Mayday. Mayday.
我失去控制了
Lost positive control.
你干什么
What're you doing?
信号连不上了
The signal's not connecting.
简
Jane.
快跑
Come on.
你还好吧
Are you all right?
你救了我
You save my life.
是啊 没错
Yeah. I guess I did.
- 达西 - 简
- Darcy? - Jane.
伊恩
Ian.
塞尔维格
Selvig.
飞锤
Mew mew!
注意站台间隙
Mind the gap.
怎么去格林威治
How do I get to Greenwich?
上车 坐三站
Take this train, three stops.
注意站台间隙
Mind the gap.
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
没时间了
We're out of time.
简
Jane.
托尔
Thor.
太晚了
We're too late.
天体汇聚已达最佳状态
The Convergence is at its peak.
这东西能阻止他吗
Can those things stop him?
在这儿不行
Not from here.
我们没法接近他
We can't get close enough.
我能
I can.
马勒基斯
Malekith.
黑暗回来了 阿斯加德人
Darkness returns, Asgardian.
你是来看宇宙湮灭的吗
Have you come to witness the end of the universe?
我是来受降的
I've come to accept your surrender.
你觉得你能阻止吗
You think you can stop this?
以太是不可摧毁的
The Aether cannot be destroyed.
但你不是
But you can.
托尔
Thor!
不要
No.
简
Jane.
大家还好吧
Everybody okay?
他会回来的
He's gonna come back.
就是…
Except, you know...
上次他一走就是两年
last time he was gone for like two years.
他才走了两天
Well, it's only been two days, so...
他走之前说什么了吗
Did he say anything before he left?
说了 他得跟他父王做些解释
Yeah, he had to figure some stuff out with his father,
我们逃出来的时候
he kinda committed treason
他犯了叛国罪
on our way out.
你曾说 不会有比我更贤明的君主
You once said, there would never be a wiser king than me.
你错了
You were wrong.
九大王国汇聚在一起
The Alignment has broght all the realms together,
他们都看到你用生命拯救了他们
every one of them saw you offer your life to save them.
阿斯加德要如何回报它新的国王呢
What can Asgard offer its new king in return?
我的生活
My life.
父王 我不能做国王
Father I cannot be king of Asgard.
我会用一生竭力保卫九大王国
I will protect Asgard and all the realms with my last and every breath,
但坐在王位上可办不到
but I cannot do so from that chair.
洛基虽有不是
Loki, for all his grave imbalance
却懂得一些我永远学不会的道理
understood rule as I know I never will.
王位所带来的残忍和牺牲
The brutality, the sacrifice.
会改变一个人
It changes you.
我宁可做好人 也不愿做明主
I'd rather be a good man, than a great king.
这是我儿子的意愿 还是他爱的女人的意思
Is this my son I hear, or the woman he loves.
我从没觉得是母亲在左右您的决定
When you speak, do I never hear mother's voice.
我不是为了简 父王
This is not for Jane, father.
她不知道我要说什么
She does not know what I came here to say.
禁止我见她
Now, forbid me to see her,
或是同意她与我共同治国 都无济于事
or say she can rule by my side, it changes nothing.
一个儿子太过渴求王位
One son who wanted the throne too much,
另一个却弃之而去
another who will not take it.
这就是我留给后世的吗
Is this my legacy?
洛基光荣牺牲
Loki died with honor.
我也要尽力而为 这还不够吗
I shall try to live the same, is that not legacy enough?
只要你配得上它
It belongs to you
它就是你的
if you're worthy of it.
我会尽力的
I shall try to.
我不能祝福你
I cannot give you my blessing,
也不能祝你好运
nor can I wish you good fortune.
我知道
I know.
即使我为我儿子如今的为人而骄傲
If I were proud of the man my son had become,
我也不能说出来
even that, I could not say.
但我会在心里赞许你
It would speak only from my heart.
去吧
Go.
我的儿子
My son.
谢谢 父王
Thank you, father.
不
No.
该谢谢你
Thank you.
向二位介绍
I present to you
收集者坦利亚·蒂万
Taneleer Tivan, the Collector.
阿斯加德人 真是荣幸
Asgardians. It's an honor.
你知道我们为何而来
You know why we're here.
是的
Of course.
但容我问一句
But if I may ask.
为什么不保管在你们那儿呢
Why not keep it secure in your own vault?
宇宙魔方已经在阿斯加德了
The Tesseract is already on Asgard.
不该把两颗无限宝石放得太近
It's not wise to keep two Infinity Stone so close together.
很明智
That's very wise.
我保证
I can assure you
在我手里
it will be absolutely safe here
一定万无一失
in my collection.
务必保管好
See that it is.
一个拿到
One down,
还剩五个
five to go.
六颗无限宝石分别代表
空间 时间 灵魂 现实 力量 意志
原由包括收集者在内的宇宙元老们保管
集齐宝石者可拥有支配宇宙的无限神力
而灭霸将六颗宝石制作成了"无限手套"
可以说是终极神器